[Music]
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Heat.
[Music]
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome back to Ask Abijit.
Today we are in the 269th episode. I
hope everybody is doing fantastic. Thank
you so much for being on this live
stream with me with your questions. We
will take questions as many as possible.
Super chat, non-super chat, whatever you
decide. Uh we'll take as many as
possible over the next couple of hours
roughly. And let us see who all is there
on the live chat. I can see Benjamin
Netanyahu. I can see Rashmir from
Rajasthan. Gorish KBJ Dikshit
uh Kumar Kanesk Dave Akash Kotak
anonymous scientist Bonjouro
nationalist Mr. Saxa Kal Singh from
Melbourne.
Raja Akash Kumar. Dave Ash Dave Akash
Kotak from London. Vehav Dangra from
Tokyo Japan. Rohit Janged. Uh
Geopolitical Dubai from Indor. Rahul
Dunak. Kani Kumar Kanish Ashish Karan.
Manoj Zawar. Who else do we have? I can
see Gopinathra IP1s MC Leavin from
Hawaii. Sher uh anonymous Rashik Odin,
Vikas PJ, Vamshi, Khaleim, myself,
Vimla, Chri, Lonely Raccoon, uh Chetan,
Arada, Arindam Roy, uh good evening sir.
Thank you so much. Thank you. Uh Rick
Duta, Sep Krishna, Mr. Iron, Jay Dit
once again. Uh I can see uh Shri Ram
Chand Chandraa Namaha Ankita good
evening Chaitan Aradia Rick Duta Prrenav
Polar Bear Shubam Dubet Gopinat and so
many other people anonymous is there
Sher is there Nyer Happy Sharma Vikash
PJ and everybody else. So thank you so
much all of you for being on the live
chat and let us take some questions. Uh
Gorish is from Dublin. Good evening uh
to you sir and everybody else.
So let's take some questions. What do we
have? Ashish Karan has asked recent Indo
Bhutan talks is it possible is it
possible to get Bhutan on board that
Dalai Lama is could be reborn at a
neutral place like Bhutan plausible
deniability? No, there's no plausible
denial deniability. There's no question
of plausible deniability. We have taken
this forward. Uh of course Bhutan will
be on board. Bhutan is another Buddhist
nation. Uh they practiced they practice
Tibetan Buddhism. No question about it.
So they will be perfectly on board with
what we do and there's no well it's it's
well it's not entirely impossible that
the next Dalai Lama I mean the the the
current Dalai Lama could be reincarnated
maybe in Bhutan but most likely it'll
happen among somewhere among the Tibetan
diaspora the majority of which is in
Bharatwash in India. So uh there's no
need for plausible deniability. We have
taken this forward. India has taken this
forward and we are not going to hide
behind plausible deniability or
whatever. This is out in the open
between us and China. So there we have
it. Okay. Uh Kumar Kanesk says as India
and the US are
um long-term adversaries then why do
they did they send an Indian astronaut
in I I in the international space
station and let India develop space
technology to launch Gaganyan and build
space station etc. Look the technology
we are build we are developing is baby
steps. They are on the verge of reaching
Mars in a in a few years. We are talking
about reaching earth orbit low earth
orbit and sending an astronaut to the
ISS is no big deal. It's not something
that gives India tremendous strategic
advantage. Right? But it's good optics.
Indians celebrate when there's an Indian
astronaut who goes to the international
space station and Indians will think yes
the US is our best friend most reliable
friend. Look, they have done us such a
great favor by sending an Indian
astronaut to the International Space
Station. It's nothing for them and we've
we've paid for it. We have paid for it.
It's not like they're doing it for free
and they are letting India develop space
technology, launch gaga, build space
station. Well, we are doing it
ourselves. We don't need their
permission or approval to do that.
Right? We are I mean they regard us as a
long-term adversary. We don't regard
anybody as an adversary. We simply want
to do our own thing. Leave us alone. We
will we want to be friends with
everybody. We want to cooperate with
everybody and we will rise as far as we
can rise and our historic position was
number one and that's what worries
people. So that's the deal. It's just
optics sending an Indian astronaut to
the international space station. It's
optics
and we have paid for it. So
Benjamin Natanyub says why do you always
say I will never go against Pakistan? I
don't know what you're talking about
sir. I have never said this or that.
I've
Yeah.
Uh Arind Roy once again good evening.
Thank you. John says uh you once said
that Indians are first of all let me
remind you all uh since I've taken this
well I'll take this but please remember
I have put this in the title of the
video I have put it is the pinned
comment. I am going to take questions
about geopolitics today. May I please
remind you all you you all as as as Shri
Donald Trump G would say thank you for
your attention to this matter. I will
only take questions about geopolitics
since I clicked on this and I took this.
So I'll take this but going forward I'll
only take questions about geopolitics.
So Indians are on a starvation diet. I
said that yes what was our D diet like
before the invasion began. Uh read the
book called Manasa. I have done this at
least two three times on previous live
chats. Uh since you have asked me, I
will I will quickly show you what the
book looks like and you can see for
yourself what our diet was like about
800 900 years ago.
And uh yeah, this is great uh for other
YouTubers who may be watching. They can
make a video about this for sure. I have
no issue with that. So take a look at
this. This is the manas lassa. Is this
the Sanskrit version or the English
version? Let's quickly see. uh it will
take a second to load and let's let's
smallify it a little bit and this is the
book now I'll not go through it and look
for the portions where it has uh uh
references to diet uh this is the
Sanskrit version clearly okay and
there's there's an English version also
my point is if you read this book you
will come to know what the Indian diet
was like before the starvation period
which was imposed upon us by the uh
British and European occupiers who
starved our ancestors to death. I mean,
hundreds of millions of us died, right?
Okay. Uh, Anka G has gifted 10
memberships. Thank you so much, ma'am.
That's so kind of you. I really
appreciate that. Thank you so much. God
bless you, ma'am. Okay.
Godliness says, "Do you believe Isra has
achieved all its goals or at least the
core objective of destroying Iranian
proxies? Trump is pushing for a
ceasefire in Gaza, but real daddy
Netanyahu is still on the hunt.
So when it comes to Iran,
this history between the two nations, uh
there's been cooperation, there's been
an adversarial relationship and the
overall the relationship has been marked
by this adversarial nature. So during
the time of the Sha who was a US puppet,
uh the two nations Iran and Israel had
excellent relations. Then you had the uh
uh Islamic revolution that happened I
think in 1979 and u the Islamic
government of Iran u under uh uh ayati
uh it it denounced Israel it says it
said that Israel has no right to exist.
It called Iran, it called Israel the
small small Satan shaitan. The great
shaitan was wasan burg obviously is the
US from their perspective right and uh
and they said that Israel has no right
to exist and it needs to be wiped off
the map. That's the kind of attitude the
the Islamic government of Iran has had
ever since during the Iran Iraq war the
two nations cooperated. Israel provided
supplies, weapons and arms and and
ammunition to Iran. Okay. Well, that's
also there and you can you can see my
previous videos to understand why it was
the case. Uh then after the fall uh of
Saddam after the end of the Iran Iraq
war and eventually Saddam Hussein was
was ousted by the Americans and so on.
So the the relationship went back to
being an adversarial relationship. Uh so
that's the deal. Now Iran has nuclear
ambitions. They have a nuclear program.
uh they may have certain amount of file
material that could be very quickly
enriched to uh weapons grade levels 90%
plus purity right from from
yellow kish stuff to actual uranium
metal and with that in mind you have to
understand what Israel's objectives are
when it comes to Iran they want to
permanently dnuclearize Iran that's
number one that's the most urgent thing
that they want to achieve that's the
most urgent goal from Israel's
perspective, the denuclearization of
Iran. That's number one. Number two,
ideally regime change in Thran and the
Sha returns or the son of the Sha
returns and becomes a new US and Israeli
puppet. That way Iran becomes gets
completely defanged, becomes once again
a vasal of the Americans and by
extension that of Israel, right? Uh and
then once if that happens, then the
proxies don't even matter anymore. the
proxies become the masterless proxies,
allies, the Houthis, the the Shia
militias in Iraq, Hezbollah, Hamas,
whatever you want to Yeah. All those all
those assets that Iran has. So the way I
see it, Netanyahu had two objectives.
One was denuclearization of Iran.
Second, even bigger regime change. And
he has achieved neither of the
objectives. The Americans under Mr.
Trump. They did deploy B2 bombers over
Iran. They did uh uh hit Iranian nuclear
sites like Ferdo, Natans, Isvahan, etc.
with bunker busting bombs. And Trump has
claimed that they have obliterated
Iran's nuclear program. But Pentagon
assessments, multiple intelligence
assessments from the US that have come
out, they say that it's not really
caused any major damage. At most, Iran's
nuclear program has been delayed by 3 to
6 months. There's no radiation that's
come out which means that none of the
uranium was hit and Trump had been
foreshadowing his strikes on Iran for at
least 2 weeks before he actually did
that. So Iran had ample time to take out
their their equipment and file material
from those nuclear sites and you have
satellite imagery that corroborates this
that this actually happened. They they
had big long convoys of trucks taking
stuff out, right? So with that
understood,
what's what's what's Israel achieved?
They have achieved neither of their big
goals, denuclearization or regime
change. Neither of those things. They
seem to have suppressed the air defenses
in Iran and uh they achieved air
dominance, air superiority over Iranian
airspace, which is a big achievement.
But yet they have not achieved the core
object objectives. Iran still has
probably a huge stockpile of drones and
various kinds of missiles, ballistic as
well as cruise missiles. Their nuclear
program is more or less fine. A delay of
6 months is no big deal. Some of their
uh top leadership has been uh
eliminated, assassinated, IRGC
commanders, nuclear scientists and all,
but Iran has a big population. They'll
find a way to replace that. So overall,
Israel hasn't achieved anything
unfortunately from their perspective.
Okay. uh and Netanyahu faces personal
troubles. There is there are like two
corruption cases against him and in
order to to sidestep those he would have
had he would have wanted to achieve a
huge victory the kind of victory no
other Israeli leader has had in the past
and that's not happened unfortunately.
So Trump has ended up not helping
Netanyahu. He has achieved what he says
is peace. Let's see how long it lasts. I
I believe it will last for a while this
peace. Um and Gaza, well that's a whole
different story. Trump wants peace in
Gaza as well and Netanyahu doesn't want
he wants Gaza to go on. So yeah, that's
the situation. All right, I hope that
explains it. Rashi Guden says, "Do you
think RAW is better than Mossad or CIA?"
Well, I am not a person who has any
connections in RAW. I don't have any
connections in Mossad. I don't have any
connections in the CIA. With that said,
if you well, how can I how can I make an
assessment setting from looking from the
outside? These are very secretive
agencies, right? Um, so for for us
civilians, there's no way to make a
proper informed uh assessment or or
evaluation of the capabilities and
assign scores to each of them and then
see which score is the biggest. I I
don't know. The MOSAD obviously has it
its reputation precedes it. uh probably
one of the best if not the best uh
intelligence agency
in the world. Um CI also has a long long
long track record of doing well
fantastic things from their perspective
right and Ro also well Ro is also row so
I I can't say really can't really say uh
but from the long if you if you look at
the whole track record this past since
1950 essentially and I would say Mosad
and CI would be neck to neck raw well we
don't really know about their successes
or failures or whatever too much because
it's all kept under wrap I can't really
make an assessment.
Okay. A Chint Anand says, "Bya, you have
implied that treaties are meant to be
broken." Well, I haven't implied that
treaties are meant to be broken. I have
said that if a treaty exists that is
detrimental to my interests, there is no
reason for me to continue uh with the
treaty and I've given multiple examples
of that. Right? For example, the uh
China the the treaty the U the Chinese
had with the UK about Hong Kong, one
nation, two systems. They walked away
from it unilaterally. They said it's
it's been enough time and we no longer
recognize this treaty. They can walk
away from it unilaterally because it's
it doesn't serve their national
interests. The Americans walked away
from the JCPOA, the joint comprehensive
plan of action, the Iran nuclear deal.
Trump walked away from that
unilaterally, right? Once again, it it
they can do it. Uh
so the point is if a treaty is
detrimental to our national interest
then we have there is we are under no
obligation to continue to abide by the
treaty with that understood. So treaties
aren't meant to be broken but sometimes
treaties are imposed upon you by force.
Such treaties when you are strong enough
you should walk away from them. Or let's
say you have a leader who did not
understand what your national interest
was and then that leader your leader 70
years ago or whatever signed a treaty.
Well, today you understand that it is it
was detrimental to your national
interest. You can walk away from it.
Okay, that's a deal. You don't have to
break every treaty. Most treaties that
you enter into, you enter into those
treaties willingly. You enter into those
treaties after considering all the pros
and cons and you uh negotiate it
properly such that it is ideally
mutually beneficial to both parties or
multiple parties. That's how you
typically do it. But sometimes you have
treaties that are bad. One example is
the Indust treaty. Terrible treaty.
Absolutely horrendously one-sided
treaty. Probably the most unequal treaty
in the history of humankind. And we have
finally walked away from it. And I would
like to thank Prime Minister Modi for
taking this uh this this step overdue,
long overdue. and very very welcome
step. Thank you so much. With that said,
uh Achinia says, "Does that mean that we
can also back off from India recognizing
Tibet as part of China?" Absolutely. And
what's happened a couple of days ago, uh
his holiness Dalai Lama stating that the
reincarnation, his reincarnation will
happen as per established procedure, as
per tradition without any external
interference by China. Well, that's that
essentially says that you know China
doesn't control the central issue when
it comes to Tibet which is the
reincarnation if of his holiness the
highest authority in in present day
Buddhism. So so that itself signals to
the entire world that China doesn't have
complete control over Tibet which means
Tibet is a disputed territory. So we're
going to ramp it up slowly as as and
when required. But yes, we can certainly
back off from recognizing Tibet as part
of China. And we can do it step by step
slowly sometimes sometimes implicitly
like what we have done here like what
his holiness has helped us do. And yes
uh and the government may take its time.
It may act diplomatically.
But for us we are under no such
diplomatic obligations. So let us put it
out in the public domain that Tibet is a
disputed territory and China
illegitimately occupies Tibet. The
Chinese occupation of Tibet is illegal,
illegitimate, brutal and it needs to
end,
right?
Um
is this a geopolitics question? Uh Chpd
kind of gives tries to placebo its user.
It gives biased answers also in all
forms of global simulations. It never
projects the US as a loser. Well, this
is kind of a geopolitical question
because this is an extension of
geopolitics. You know, technology and uh
propaganda is an extension of
geopolitics. So that's how it goes. If I
create a large language model, an AI
system that I offer to the world, if I
create it, okay, and I control it
entirely, my minions, my employees
control all the aspects and parameters
of this uh uh large language model that
I'm offering to the world as a service,
then obviously I will always portray
India as the winner. I am biased, my
dear friends. In in case you're not
aware, I am a super biased person. I'm
always biased towards India. Okay.
So if I create a large language model
then this large language model of mine
will always
give you answers that are biased in
favor of India. No matter what you do,
no matter how you try to question it,
interro interrogate it, try to fool it,
mislead it, it will always give you
answers that will be favorable to that
will portray India in a favorable light.
Okay? And that's how it goes. The
Chinese what what is it called? Deepse
seek R1 R2. What R2 is an out I suppose
R1 I think is the one. Uh it's available
for download. So if you have a powerful
enough laptop and you download it
locally then you can make it do whatever
you want. I mean it'll it'll not be
biased. It won't have those constraints.
But the one that's online I suppose it
will be biased in favor of China. So
that's how it goes. We should not be
surprised about it. We should not be
surprised. So this is a war of
narratives. It's it's a propaganda war
and if you use these services you should
be aware that there will be inherent
biases. There won't be blatant biases.
There will be very subtle biases and
often times mo most people won't be
won't even be aware of the existence of
these biases. And you know most what
most people do on Twitter, hey Grock, is
this true? And whatever Grock says it's
it's the gospel truth as as if it was
written in the Bible or something,
right? Gospel truth. And and people
these days if they if if they want to
fact check something they will open up
their phone and they'll say hey Chhat
GPD what about what's the answer to this
and whatever Chip says that's the truth
that's it GPDI
now there's no question about what the
truth is so that's how people's minds
are um and that's why it's so easy to
fool them and that's why chd and all
these LLMs they are very powerful uh
tools in the propaganda toolkit of the
major powers all Right. Please be aware
of this my dear friends.
GPO African Skipio.
Okay. As a follow-up to the Dalai Lama
question, how do you see this
realistically play out visav Tibet?
Visav visav Tibet. Will it work as we
intend?
what is the intention of making uh first
of all we to ask ourselves what's the
intention of uh of of the of his
holiness making this uh statement now
the assertion that his reincarnation
will proceed as per tradition the the
objective of that is to once again tell
the world that Tibet is a disputed
territory Tibet is is China's hold on
Tibet is illegitimate and so on that's
that's what we intended by doing this
now it will play out in a variety of
different ways and if you want to play
out if you want to understand how it
could play out then watch my u uh the
the latest episode of geo strategy that
came out day before yesterday the Tibet
section the Dalai Lama section in which
I have gone into great detail and I've
put out like five different uh forecasts
with multiple scenarios as to how this
will play out uh will it work as we
intend it it it is working the way we
intended see what's happened actually is
that the Chinese are openly blatantly
out in the public supporting Pakistan.
When Operation Synindur was happening,
they were giving real-time information
and data to Pakistan to counter us. Uh
and that's very concerning because the
Chinese seem to have uh spy satellites
in position above our our you know above
outside of Earth, outside of the
atmosphere and keeping an eye on us.
That's something we're going to have to
take very seriously and we're going to
have to counter that with satellites of
our own. We're going to have to bolster
and augment our satellite network. But
the point is the Chinese
have very have made it very clear to us
that they are our enemies and they no
longer have any intention of of uh uh
seeking friendship with us like they
were claiming last year. So now that
they have made it absolutely 100% clear
to us. So that's why we have taken this
step. Okay. It's in response to Chinese
provocations and it's going to work the
way we intended. It's it's going to work
the Chinese the way the Chinese wanted
it to work. The Chinese asked for it. So
we have given it to them and now we're
going to be more assertive about this.
So what's the worst case scenario? China
says you are our enemies. Well, you are
China is anyway behaving as our enemy.
Um so we are essentially telling the
world that we agree that China is not
going to be our friend. We now regard
China as an adversarial nation. their
their claims of friendship were all
false and we're going to do everything
in our power to ensure that China
doesn't get the upper hand over us. So
with these uh symbolic statements
these these indicative statements like
like what happened which which raises
the Tibet issue and makes Tibet again a
gray area a disputed area. With that, we
also have to take real action of
bolstering our armed forces of of
ramping up our up our missile
production, our border uh infrastructure
uh along the LACE, the the India Tibet
border, uh augmenting uh all our
weaponry, air defense systems, uh naval
naval systems, all of that. We need to
do all that cyber security. So all of
this has to happen at the same time. our
satellite satellite network. We need to
put up more satellites in space that can
keep an eye on occupied Tibet and other
Chinese activities, Pakistani
activities. We need to augment the Navic
system so much more. So as long as we do
these things, it's going to have the
effect that we want, which is to
increase u our security visav China. So
yeah, it's it's going to be a work in
progress over the next decade
essentially.
Um, Wooden Armor says, "Do you believe
EU the quality of the of life in the
European Union will go down given that
it's mostly a service-based economy and
AI will disrupt it?" A lot of things
will disrupt uh the quality of life in
the EU. The first thing that will
disrupt the quality of life in the EU is
the large scale un unraveled
unmititigated
um illegal immigration that's happening
that's that's flowing into the EU.
That's going to destroy their quality of
life. They will no longer have space
safe spaces where they can sit and have
siestas in public and uh have those have
you know those bistos and cafes and sip
sip coffee all day. Whatever they do,
that's not going to happen. Uh secondly,
because each nation in in NATO is now
going to have to ramp up its uh uh you
know it its uh defense budget from two
less than 2% of GDP to 5% of GDP that's
going to cut down on the public welfare
welfare schemes and um all all of that
you know u the welfare state system that
all the EU nations have. So that's going
to bring the quality of life down. Um
and of course AI is going to have its
own impact on on this. So overall the
next 10 years the quality of life is
going to come down significantly in the
EU region which is very unfortunate but
it is what it is. These are the cycles
of history and we are witnessing them in
real time. 10 years from now it's going
to be a different kind of Europe
definitely.
Uh
Napoleon Singh Shikhawad says how Israel
allowed Nazi to be Mossad agents.
I am not aware of this person. Uh let me
quickly Google the person. I'm not aware
of who this person is. Otto Scorzini.
Who was Otto Scorzini? Otto Scorzini.
Austrianborn German SS
agent SSand
fur in the waffin SS. Uh oh yeah this
this guy Egypt etc. Well well if you're
useful you're useful. You see that's how
it goes. If a person is useful and as as
long as the person is willing to offer
their services, you don't trust them.
But do you use them works? Why not? You
have got to be pragmatic in life. You
can't be idealistic especially when it
comes to national security when it comes
to uh counter intelligence and all of
that. You can even use the enemy's
agents. If the enemy's agent is willing
to offer you services for a price, you
use the services. You don't trust the
person. You verify constantly what they
are doing. You spy on them, but you use
their services and that's how it goes.
Lesson to be learned.
Uh
anonymous scientist says Prime Minister
Modi was warmly received with a bare hug
by uh Mr. Mle in Argentina 10 minutes
ago. Well, okay, breaking news. How
important is Argentina to India?
Argentina is an important uh nation in
Latin America. pretty large nation. The
second largest nation in Latin America.
Let's take a look at it. Right. Let's go
to the map. We haven't opened the map
today thus far. Yeah, it's been Yeah.
Okay. So, let's go westwards. We cross
the Atlantic. We go southwards. And here
we have Argentina. Pretty nice cold
place actually. It's a pretty big
country. The second largest nation in
South America. Lots of resources, lots
of mineral and natural resources. Pretty
big country.
uh they have a territorial dispute with
the UK, the Malvvenas islands that the
UK calls the Faulland Islands and the UK
occupies this Argentina claims this and
so on. It's it's a pretty important
country. Um it's a large country with uh
yeah so I I say it's a pretty important
country and uh it's one of the nations
that's part of the global south. India
should in my opinion be uh the leader of
the global south. China doesn't want to
play the role. China wants to play
imperial superpower games. Let them try
and play those games. Okay, let them
try. Let them try and do do all that.
India should build consensus among the
global south. India should reach out to
every member of the global south. Prime
Minister Modi was on a trip to multiple
nations. Is on a trip to multiple
nations. He was in Ghana recently in in
the Caribbean region. Uh Trinidad if I'm
not mistaken. Now he's in Argentina.
He's on this this trip to reach out to
as many uh important nations as possible
and Argentina itself as as a as the
second largest nation in Latin America.
It's pretty important quite important
and we should have great relations with
Argentina and Brazil and everybody else.
So I think it's a great step.
Abishekav says what's Russia's
justification for the Crimea invasion?
Well, Crimea was always part of Russia.
That's the justification.
That's the justification. It's always
been part of a shared history.
So that's it. That's your answer, sir.
Um
Geo Warrior says, "How should our
foreign service be restructured to serve
our geopolitical interests better?" Not
saying it's bad now, but just wanted
your opinion. See the first thing I we
can see is that we have approximately
16 to700
diplomats total
1,600 to 1,700.
Uh is that enough to take on the world
to to engage with the world? Singapore
has more diplomats than India.
The US has more than 10,000 diplomats,
maybe around 20,000 perhaps. Russia has
more than 10,000 diplomats. You want to
be able to engage with every single
nation in the world. You need to have
multiple people engaging with each
nation. We need to have specialists that
are that specialize in the history and
culture and politics of each nation.
Even a small nation like Sioto may
principe principe or Botswana
or whatever elsetoonga.
We need to have specialists in each
nation. People who speak the local
language. People who can speak the tool
language, the language that they speak
in Ghana, for example, the language they
speak in Argentina, which is the Spanish
of Argentina, whatever. We need to have
people who understand the local
politics, the local history. You need to
have specialists. We need to have
specialists in each nation, military
specialists,
uh agricultural specialists, uh
geoengineering specialists who are also
diplomats.
You need to have this sort of
specialization within the IFS
and you need to have a much more
expanded IFS. We a nation of India's
scale and magnitude needs at least
10,000 diplomats.
Of course, we have these different
ministries in India and the various uh
officers within each ministry, they also
serve as diplomats during negotiations
and whatever. But you need specialists
within the IFS. So my opinion is very
clear. We need to have a much more
expanded IFS. They should allow lateral
entry. They should have consultants,
people who are not really within the IFS
but will consult for the IFS as and when
required can be deployed if required and
so on. It needs to become a much larger
much more capable much broader
organization with lots of specialists as
well as lots of generalists. That's what
you need. That's what needs to happen
and well high time for that to happen.
Okay. Literally, Officer K says, "Global
sentiment towards Israel, especially
among Gen Z millennials, is at an
all-time low, especially in key nations
like the US. When do you think, if ever,
will this reflect in policy towards
Israel?
When it comes to Okay, see, let's talk
about the US because you have mentioned
the US. Uh first of all when it comes to
India I'm not sure if the sentiment in
India towards Israel is is at an
all-time low. I don't think so. There
will be some sections of Indian society
whatever percentage you would have put
there who will never support Israel who
will always be virulently opposed to
Israel but overall most Indians are have
a pretty positive uh view of Isra. So
let's not discuss India let's discuss
the US. in the US. I haven't seen
polling figures or data or statistics,
but it does look like there's a downward
uh trend in u the way Israel is
regarded. That's what it looks like. Uh
okay, in the absence of data, I cannot
say for sure, but it's it's it's
possible.
Um the question then is when will this
reflect in policy, US policy towards
Israel? Not anytime soon. So you see
this is the deal. This is the deal my
friends. In a democracy,
public sentiment should drive national
policy.
That's what a democracy is supposed to
be. National policy should reflect the
will of the people. Correct? Yes. No.
Yes. Yes. Friends. Yes. My dear viewers,
public policy in a democracy should
reflect the will of the people. Now in
the US it's let's assume that uh 51% of
people uh see don't have a very good
opinion of Israel
maybe 60% let's say whatever number
let's put out a hypothetical number
let's say 60% of of Americans don't see
Israel very positively so then in that
case should US policy not be kind of
reflective of that sentiment towards
Israel but that's never going to
Okay. So then the question arises, is
the US really a democracy?
That's how it goes. You see, public
sentiment doesn't really matter in the
US. The politicians will do what
politicians do. Uh
so when it comes to the US, it looks
like this will never reflect in American
policy towards Israel. US policy will
always put Israel first. Mr. Trump has
said, "Israel is our number one ally. We
have to do whatever it takes to support
Israel." Not those words, but I'm
paraphrasing. Okay? You get, please
understand what I mean. Don't quote me
on that. The stand of Mr. Trump is that
Israel is our prime ally and we have to
do whatever it takes to support Israel.
We don't have to necessarily support the
prime minister, the current prime
minister of Israel. We don't support
individual politicians, but we support
the nation and we'll stand by the
nation. will do whatever it takes to to
uh ensure that the nations Israel as a
nation its interests are always taken
care of. That's always been the US
policy for the longest time
since uh well since the the Johnson era
I would say after JFK Johnson was the
prime was the president of the US after
JFK's assassination and so the US policy
has been extremely pro-Israel
almost like Israel first ever since uh
the Johnson era so even if there is
significant sentiment against Israel in
the US among the gen Z among the
millennials US official policy will
always favor Israel that's how I see it
what's the reasons for that well that's
a long diff that's a whole different
story
okayish
K says as you mentioned the US or any
other powerful nation tends to make
other nations its vasal how did India
manage to avoid become one in Congress
rule okay which Congress rule are you
referring to there have been so many
Congress rules 20th century Congress
rule
India was well you could say a Soviet
vasal kind of
during the cold during the first cold
war the 20th century cold war which
ended let's say around 1999 thereabouts
that during that period India was more
more or less part of the Soviet uh
it was you could perhaps you could say
India was kind of a Soviet vasal right
uh and and Soviet vasalhood was very
different from American Vasalhood. Uh so
we were okay. It was fine for us. It did
compromise us to a certain small extent
but not the way you get compromised
under American Vasalhood.
Then after the dissolution of the USSR
um there was a uniolar moment for a few
years. The Americans were the only
superpower in the world. The only great
power major power superpower in the
world. There was no challenger on the
horizon. And India was a was an
insignificant nation for the longest
time
until the mid2010s
late 2010s India was insignificant.
Yeah, India was sure was a big growing
market and economy and all that but
geopolitically from a hard power
perspective India was insignificant. We
had nuclear weapons but we did not ever
you know uh use that to our advantage
um and so on. So the US did not really
care about making India their vasal
during that period of time. Uh India did
become did get deeply infiltrated by the
Americans. Uh 1991 onwards. Okay. I
assure you of that even today India is
deeply deeply penetrated and infiltrated
by by the US at various levels. Even
today it is the case. Let me just say
that. Uh but we have we never became a
vasal. Uh during the tenure of Mr. Man
Dr. Mon Singh 10 years um we did sign
this this one 123 deal agreement nuclear
agreement with the US but it never
really fortified into anything uh
anything substantial any any action on
the ground and uh Mr. Dr. Man Singh
always had this uh you know the approach
that India doesn't have any big
ambitions. We don't aspire to be a great
power. We'll just exist kind of that
sort of thing and uh that is the way
things went. So India kind of stayed
below everybody's everybody's horizon.
Nobody cared. It's only when Mr. Modi
came to power and things started
changing pretty rapidly that the world
took note of India. Slowly start started
taking note of India. And it's now that
India is now you know people are worried
about India in India growing and
becoming possibly the next China if we
get our things right. So that that is
how things went.
Puruam Pradhan says relationship between
sports and geopolitics big fan thank you
so much. Sports and geopolitics look
there's no actual relationship between
sports and geopolitics. Sports is
something that can build a national
narrative. If you are great in sports
people regard you with more respect.
Okay people admire you more. I mean
Jamaica is a tiny little nation but we
admire Jamaica because of their
sprinting team because of Usuzain Bolt
right there's a little there's a
significant amount of admiration and if
you are a reasonably okay nation from a
hard power perspective okay middle
ranking nation with from a hard power
perspective but you produce great
athletes and you win lots of golds then
you are then it's it's it's great for
propaganda then people tend to see you
as more powerful than you actually are
and sports of course has this unifying
factor
Nothing unifies a nation like success,
right? You may have all kinds of
disputes within the nation. But the
moment there is a Olympic gold or a
world cup win, everybody forgets their
differences and comes together. And a
nation that continuously keeps winning,
it has more unity within. And that's
great geopolitically. So right.
So Shabban Dub says did the US support
Israel because of the role of Jewish
scientists in developing the atom bomb
and has continued technology and
intelligence cooperation made Israel one
of America's most trusted allies over
time. The question is why did the US why
does the US support Israel?
Look in geopolitics nobody remembers
favors.
Okay?
No one remembers favors. Oh, you did
something great for me 50 years ago, so
that's why I'll be favorably inclined
towards you. That doesn't work in
geopolitics. No one cares. The only
thing that matters in geopolitics is
your utility to me today. You may have
done great things for me 50 years ago,
but in geopolitics
that such sentimentality doesn't work.
There is no place for sentiment in
geopolitics. The only parameters that
are that are considered in geopolitical
calculations is utility. America looks
at Pakistan. Ah useful. We can we can
use Pakistan to bleed India for 30 years
using Pakistani terrorism as our proxy.
That's that's how it is useful. In the
past Pakistan backstabbed us multiple
times but who we don't care. Pakistan is
still useful. That's how it works.
So Jewish scientists of course there
were some Jewish scientists who
developed the atomic who were who had a
role in developing the atom bomb but
that those were American scientists
right
I mean you have many Indian scientists
in America so by the same logic
shouldn't there have shouldn't the US
support India very much but it's not the
case
right think about it there are many
Chinese origin scientists in the US who
have developed developed various things
right I One of the scientists who
developed stealth technology for the
Americans was Indian Indian origin guy.
They jailed him for espionage.
Do you know that?
So it doesn't work like that. This is
not the reason why the US keeps
supporting Israel and all that. There
are there are other reasons for that.
All right? That's that's all I'll tell
you. Please think logically. Please look
at counter examples. When you want to
understand something and you see some
data that supports what you believe,
please always ask yourself, do we have
counter examples that don't support what
I believe or what I want to believe?
That's how you think critically.
You look at counter examples. You look
at things from a 360°ree perspective.
You look at historical precedents.
That's how you examine things. That's
how you think critically. Just because
there are like some examples that
support what I believe deep inside
doesn't mean that you should just jump
to the conclusion. Always look at other
examples then you will see that it
doesn't really work that way. Okay.
Okay.
Adita says any views on COR development
of electric jet engine could we produce
civil aircraft in the future and
supporting amca which is with its
engine. What is senor? I'm not aware of
this. Looks like it's more breaking
news. Let's let's let's Google it and
find out what is Siri.
Siri
um what electric
jet engine?
What is this? Siri
tests electric jet engine for India.
Let's see what this is. Open up, bro. Uh
Senor tests electric jet engine in
India. It has successfully tested what
it claims is the world's first all
electric jet engine in Pune etc. Let's
see what the technology is. Norwegian
aerospace company with Indian subsidiary
reported that its engine prototype
exceeded the design intent of 40,000 RPM
and 10 kgf thrust as measured by a load
cell and so on so forth ground test. But
what's the technology? It's developing a
tip-driven propulsion system using
distributed edge motors, mounted motors,
southern hub mounted engine built for
thrust from 1 kilon to 90 plus kon. The
design aims to support ranges exceeding
4,000 km. UAV engine commercialization,
etc. Senior engine architecture removes
the need for combustion chambers and
high-cost alloys.
Uh, power source agnostic engine can
work with both battery and hydrogen
electric energy sources. I'm still not
clear about what the what what the
mechanism is. Let's see this idw
electric all electric jet engine. Son
knows etc etc etc. Uh traditional jets
relies on fossil fuels but seror's all
electric design leverages advanced
battery technology electric propulsion
to eliminate emissions entirely.
So our view
okay I'll have to look into this in
detail I'll not go do the do the
research right now looks intriguing
so they don't what's this what what
drives what moti what is the motivating
factor for the the RPM what's the power
source is the question is it batteries
that would be shocking and I'll be very
pleased with that
uh is it hydrogen fuel even that would
be fine I'm not sure all electric means
it looks like it's it's driven It's its
power source is just a battery pack.
That would be great. I've not heard of
such technology before. So, I'll look
into this. This is the first time I'm
hearing about it. Very interesting piece
of news. And I shall uh look into this
in more detail. If if this works out and
if it has a output of 90 kontons for
example, depending on the size of the
engine, well, I think one or two engines
on a on a jet aircraft will be
tremendous. Of course, you know, can you
super cruise with that? Does it can you
can you cross the speed of sound? All
all of these questions are there, but
looks very promising to me. Looks
promising for sure.
Uh really now says, "Do you know if it's
true Chinese harvest the organs of
fallong fallong people even though
they're natives? They even sell human
meat.
Using lefto is horrific." I don't know.
There's all kinds of rumors that come
out of China. There's this persistent
rumor that China, you know, the Chinese
have this uh very harsh death penalty
system. They execute like well over
10,000 people every year. And I've
always been hearing about this for the
longest time, 20 years plus, that the
Chinese when they execute somebody, they
harvest the organs.
And I've heard that there is a lot of
oppression that the the Chinese have
oppressed the the Falong people for
whatever reason. I'm not sure what the
reason is. Maybe it's a religious cult
or whatever according to China. Uh but
yeah, I've heard about this. I don't
know if it's true. I've heard the
rumors, the very persistent rumors, but
I do not know if this is true. Can't
unless you have sources on the ground,
you can't tell. So, I don't know.
Uh Adit Kumar says, "What are your
thoughts on the Gatak UCAV?
Can it act as an unmanned bomber for the
IIAF? Should we rent Russian bombers?"
Alternatively,
um, the Gatak UCAV, it was called the
DRDO Aura earlier. Now it's called the
Gatak. It reminds me of the Russian
Oknik. The Okothnik, is it a bomber or
is it is it a fighter interceptor? Uh,
let's let's first take a look at the
Okothnik. Oknik. Uh, is it a I think
let's see.
The Oknik is a Russian stealth heavy
unmanned combat aerial vehicle. This is
also a UCAV unmanned combat aerial
vehicle
and uh yeah so I think it's it would be
under serial production now. Um yeah so
that's the deal with Oknik. how the di
the gatak
the gataka this is still under
production under under development
obviously
um not sure oh as always please don't
rely on Wikipedia too much because it is
it is likely to have uh distortions and
misrepresentations and so on but yeah so
the question is can it okay so this is
an this is an unmanned a combat aerial
vehicle
which means means that it will be used
for combat. It will be stealthy, hard to
detect and that that gives it
advantages. So you can bring it into
close proximity with whoever you want to
combat with and take those guys down. So
let's say you have a Pakistani fighter
jet or or or a Chinese fighter jet that
you want to engage and you send the
gatak which is stealthy so they can't
detect it on radar until it's too late
and you come as close as possible and
then you fire maybe Astra missiles or
whatever and at a reasonably close
distance there's no way you can evade
the Astra missile. So it's it's uh an
unmanned combat aerial vehicle. It's for
combat, but you can use the Gatak design
and make it much more massive with
obviously you need testing and all that
for that. But then you can then use that
as an unmanned bomber possibly or maybe
even convert that into a man bomber like
the B2 or something. Uh so yeah, the
possibilities are endless once you get
this right. Uh should we rent Russian
bombers? We can buy Russian bombers. Why
why not still the the strategic bombers?
I think makes sense to have a few of
those. Uh that's for the government to
decide, but I think it it does make
sense to have a few uh you know those
white swan bombers or something a few of
those in our um our arsenal for sure.
Nle says why did Yugoslavia disintegrate
into six countries? What was the reason
behind the US hatred for them? Well, you
I've kind of answered your question. The
US was behind the disintegration of
Yugoslavia. See, Yugoslavia was part of
uh the Soviet block, Eastern Europe,
right? Um
the Balkan nations were all part of
Yugoslavia. Let's let's go to the map.
Let's quickly take a look at uh at the
region.
So, which nations were part of
Yugoslavia? Today, you have a bunch of
nations in the Balkan region, right?
um Bosnia, Hatsuggavina, Serbia, Kosovo,
Montenegro,
um Slovenia, Croatia, all of these used
to be part even even I think North
Macedonia if I'm not mistaken. All of
these used to be part of this large
nation called Yugoslavia.
And after the dissolution of the USSR,
Yugoslavia was broken up. And this was
done by the Americans. So there was a
civil war kind of thing. Old ethnic
hatreds came out. During the communist
period, no such thing was allowed. But
when um and and see Yugoslavia always
existed under the protection of the
USSR. The USSR was a superpower. It
could protect its allies and they
remained protected. But once the USSR
disintegrated, the Americans said that
you know what, we're going to destroy
everything the USSR created. So they
went ahead and and you could say it
sparked the conflict or encouraged the
conflict or whatever but that ended up
disintegrating Yugoslavia. What was the
reason for the US hatred for them? Well,
because they used to be part of the
Soviet block and the Americans wanted to
destroy everything the Soviets had
created because they could. It was a
uniolar moment. They could and that's
why they did that. Terrible time. 1990s.
Terrible times. Terrible civil war.
Horrific. Absolutely horrific.
Okay. Shashank says any sign in any
signs of boost in bilaterals between
India and Australia.
Well, I haven't seen any recent
developments. We have this trade deal
negotiations going on. We've already
signed a trade deal and initial trade
deal and there's going to be another
more more advanced trade deal that's
going to happen sometime maybe by the
end of this year. And uh I think India
Australia relations are great. Lots of
uh you know multi-dommain
multi-dimensional cooperation in a
variety of ways uh trade lot of trade.
We obviously are part of the quad and so
on but recent events I haven't seen much
but yeah overall the the relationship is
on a very is on a very good track is all
I can say. Okay
Moit but well thank you so much sir. I
really appreciate that. Thank you.
Wooden Armor PK says, "How relevant are
fighter jets in modern warfare and what
can India do to develop a single crystal
blade jet engine program like the
French?"
Fighter jets are still very relevant,
still relevant as as far as we know. Um,
see today we have uh lots of other
systems that have entered the battle
space. For example, drones, as we know,
uh drones of various kinds,
anti-personnel drones, anti-vehicle
drones, drones that can take out tanks
very easily if you know where to hit the
tank, right? Um and also uh kabi kaza
drones or suicide drones, those are also
very um dangerous, very uh relevant in
today's battle space uh scenarios. We
saw a lot of that during the 3-day
operation Synindur 3-day war between
India and Pakistan in which we hammered
Pakistani terrorist sites and military
infra infrastructure with uh loitering
drones, harop drones um and also
missiles of various kinds. So where do
fighter jets come into the picture is
the question. Well, ideally you want to
disable you want to suppress the enemy
air defenses. SE A suppression of enemy
air defenses. You want to achieve that
first, which means you first take out
their radars. Then you take out their
their anti-aircraft batteries, which are
anti-aircraft uh missile systems and
guns and all that. Once you take all of
that out, that's when you can send your
aircraft. And then you may have even
before that you you want to destroy
their air bases, which means you should
uh take out the runways at least make
the runways inoperative for a few hours.
you know crater the runways by hitting
the runways with very powerful missiles.
Abramos hit on a Pakistani runway will
gouge a gigantic crater then no
Pakistani aircraft can take off from
there for a few hours minimum maybe for
a few weeks depends and then once the
airspace is is sanitized and the air
defenses are suppressed properly that's
when uh fighter planes become relevant.
Ideally that's how we want to use them.
Sometimes you have to do dog fighting
which is a 20th century thing in my
opinion but sometimes we still do that
in which case you need good fighter
planes you know agile maneuverable
ideally four generation plus four plus
generation with long
um with very powerful air-to-air
missiles like the Meteor or the
augmented Astra even the regular Astra
and so on even various Russian airto-air
missiles are very effective all of that
so fighter jets are still relevant still
relevant As of now, what can India do to
develop a single single crystal blade
jet engine program? Keep on iteratively
or improving what you're doing.
Alternatively, buy borrow steel.
Whatever it takes, get it done. Buy it
from the French or the Russians. Buy,
beg, borrow, steal, whatever it takes.
National interest is paramount. Get it
done. So, we have the caviri system that
is ongoing. But I think that that
program has been stopped for now which
means something may be a foot. I don't
know what would be a foot but we'll see
about that.
Um
the rational reporter says why has India
not being able to control the west like
Israel despite having a highly
successful and significantly larger
diaspora? Is it religion? Well yeah we
are polytheists. Polytheists are hated
by the west. The west is a monotheistic
culture. the monotheism has been imposed
upon them by force by the way but they
no longer remember all of that they are
monotheists at heart and uh the original
monotheistic religion obviously was
Judaism right
um it's the original Abrahamic religion
and the other two religions came they
appeared later so Judaism Judaism
Judaism whatever it is is the original
Abrahamic religion and uh the US is a
Christian country whatever you say
whatever claims it's a Christian nation.
Okay. The US and Christians are first
class citizens. Polytheists are not
exactly first class citizens in the US.
Okay. Uh so we and the other thing is
that we have a very large diaspora.
Sure. Very successful, very rich etc.
But we are not unified. We are not
united. Indians are like cats. You can't
herd cats together. Have you ever seen a
shepherd hering cats? Cats are incapable
of being herded. They are too
individualistic. They will go in their
own direction. You'll never see seven
cats together. I once saw seven cats
together as a child, but that's a whole
different story. So,
uh, so that's how Indians are. Indians
can't unite. Indians love arguing with
each other. Indians, we have too many
differences despite being part of the
same civilization. Or you speak a
different language. or you eat onions.
Oh, you eat garlic. Oh, you eat chicken.
You you eat mutton.
This is all within the dharmic umbrella.
By the way, we we have too many
differences, too many small differences.
And we consider those differences to be
bigger than whatever unites us. And
that's why Indians despite being so
successful, so rich,
uh etc. in the US, they simply aren't
united. They exist in these little
communities, different communities. The
Telugu speaking people will be here. The
the Punjabi speaking people will be
here. The Tamil speaking people will be
here. The Marwari speaking people here.
Gujarati people here.
Bengali people here. All different all
different uh they all different exist in
different multiverses, different
universes. They will get together once
in a while for whatever but very very
seldom.
And that's why Indians simply don't
unite and Indians don't seem to be
politically active too much. There are a
a few examples. Vak is an example
obviously.
Uh he as you see as you can see he's not
doing too well. Of course he may still
possibly perhaps longshot may become the
govern governor of Ohio. We'll see about
that. Um other Indians if they want to
be politically relevant they have to
convert. Nimrata core became Nikki Haley
converted to Christianity. Push Jindal
became Bobby Jindal converted to
Christianity. Right? So that's the deal.
So that's the deal. That's the story.
Now, uh, caution world says, why is
there no independence movement in Japan
or Germany? People must know the truth
about US occupation due to internet even
if it's not taught.
Well,
I'll tell you what. In in Japan, from
the time you are 3 years old or
whatever, you go to school, you are
taught that Japan is a pacifistic
country. We believe in pacifism. We
believe in nonviolence.
Violence is evil. Weapons are evil. In
the past, we were very bad people. Our
ancestors were very evil people and they
deserved everything they got. And Japan
must never ever ever ever take up arms.
Japan must forever remain arms free.
Armies are bad. And the good Americans,
they are here to ensure that Japan never
becomes bad again. Japan was very
naughty in the past.
This is ingrained into you from the time
you were three years old and you grow up
repeating these mantras
and by the time you're 18, 20, you
believe it with with the fullest extent
of your heart.
What what what happens then? You you're
done. You simply what independence
moment will happen? Yeah, you may have a
few Yukio Mishimas who come up and try
to exhort the armed forces to to take up
arms, but they're going to laugh you off
and then you end up doing sepoku like
Yukio Mishima. Germany also same story.
20,000 years 2000 2,000th anniversary of
Armenius
routing the Romans. Nobody celebrated in
Germany. You're not taught about these
things, right? Germany also same story
as Japan. That's why education is the
the core of everything. That's why
education is so important in India as
well. May I remind you, I haven't
mentioned it yet in this episode. Well,
here you have it.
Okay.
FAL Shake says reports say that food
supplies sent to Gaza after the
so-called ceasefire are being drugged.
Videos have surfaced allegedly uh
showing people in Israel paying to watch
the bombing of Gaza yacht. My thoughts?
Um,
uh, well, I haven't seen I'm not keeping
an eye on what's happening in Gaza,
first of all, but yeah, what's happening
in Gaza is obviously a humanitarian
catastrophe. No question about it. No
question about it. Uh, that's which is
why
ideally ideally I would want the UN to
take over the UN,
right? The UN is supposedly a neutral
organization. It's the organization
that's in charge of world peace. The UN
should take over in Gaza. They should be
in charge of everything. Uh if if they
are, I don't think they are. If they
are, then they should have a proper
presence there. A UN peacekeeping force
should be there in Gaza. And then
everything should happen through the UN.
And the UN should check everything. If
food supplies are tainted, contaminated,
drugged, whatever, then those should be
checked, verified because they before
they given to the people of Gaza and so
on. Uh look, what are my thoughts about
this? the people of Israel clearly
uh don't have any love towards the
people of Gaza.
It's it's this thing this enmity goes
too deep now and I suppose Israel will
be okay with this. I suppose many people
in Israel may be okay with this. Okay,
it is what it is. Um I'm not sure about
people in Israel paying to watch the
bombing of a Gaza yacht. Not sure.
But well yeah this is a absolute
terrible tragedy and uh
yeah what can I say I the UN should
should should step in uh and stop
whatever is happening and they should
ensure that there is no terrorism that
emanates from Gaza towards Israel and
they should ensure that there is no more
fighting that that Israel does bombing
of Gaza as long as there is peace things
can go forward and maybe people can move
on with their lives uh there's no
question about the fact that Hamas has
been terrorizing Israel. They have all
these tunnels in Gaza built under
hospitals, built under what not, built
under schools and they've been launching
all kinds of missiles at Israel. And
then the October 7 it was whatever date
it was 2023 the terrorist attack against
Israel which which sparked all of this
off right.
Uh so I think Gaza needs to be uh what
needs to happen is that uh it needs to
be
uh demilitarized
and then the UN should ensure that there
is no more fighting and uh if there have
been any war crimes from from whatever
side they the people responsible for
that need to be taken need to be brought
to account I would say. Yeah it's it's a
terrible situation overall. overall. But
look, from from my perspective, I it's
it's hard for me to to have a tremendous
amount of sympathy for Gaza given the
fact that Hamas supports Pakistan. Hamas
supports Pakistan's activities in PK and
overall their their their approach
towards India has been very negative. Um
you you have to put your nation first.
But overall, I would say the UN should
take over. There should be no more
violence. Whatever is happening should
end. If if anybody has committed war
crimes or atrocities, they should be uh
taken into account and brought to
justice. No question about it. Yeah.
Uh
MK says, "If Israel ceases to exist,
does it nuke the world like the US?"
Because you said Israel someday controls
US and US nukes world. It ceases to
exist in nuclear war. What?
Look, Israel, US, two separate nations.
Okay, let's look at it that way. There
may be tenuous control here and there.
We'll not discuss that. Israel has
something called the Samson option which
says what is the Samson option? Israel
is surrounded by historical enemies.
Yes. And consider a hypothetical
scenario in which the enemies are on the
verge of destroying Israel. Israel's
military has failed and the enemies are
are on the verge of invading and
smashing Israel to bits. Hypothetical
scenario. In that scenario,
Israel will employ the the Samson option
which is a nuclear option in which it
will destroy all its enemies. So if we
we are destroyed, we'll ensure everybody
else falls with us. And they have
apparently a list of targets.
No Indian targets but interesting
targets nonetheless. Okay. In the Samson
option, some world capitals are there
allegedly. allegedly major capitals not
not Indian not in any Indian city. The
US the US also has its version of the
Samsung option which is nuke the whole
world.
If the US is in is in under imminent
danger of going under, they will launch
nuclear missiles at everybody
including nations that have done nothing
to them including India.
That's the deal. So that is the the
American augmented sansson option which
is the whole world will be destroyed if
is if the US goes down. That is their
plan. That that's so evil. Seriously,
it's incredibly evil. But that's their
plan.
Um that's all I'll say about this.
Okay.
Interesting question comes up over here.
Yes, very interesting. Vishal Nata says
recently an ex CIA operative John
Kirikao
revealed that the Pakistani nuclear
command is indeed under American control
that is it is uh controlled by an
American general and my assumption has
turned out to be true. Well, it was uh
yeah. So, yes, this this I I've seen the
video I have seen the video of this
person, this gentleman, CIA agent uh
John Kirikawa saying this the Pakistani
nuclear command is under American
control. It's an American general who
controls the Pakistani nuclear so-called
deterrent. It's American nuclear weapons
that the Pakistanis have and they are
controlled by Americans.
That's the deal. So, here we have it.
Once again, the Americans have plausible
deniability. They'll say, "No, this guy
is irrelevant or or or he's unreliable."
And this is an unofficial statement.
He's he has retired so so and so years
ago and he no longer knows what's
happening and he's making claims that
are completely false. They can make any
kind of statement. They can claim
plausible deniability,
but the fact is that it's it's amply
clear now. The so-called Pakistani
nuclear deterrent is actually American
nuclear weapons on Pakistani soil aimed
at India. Maybe at other countries also,
but mainly at India, which tells you the
relationship that the Americans have
with us and the way they see the way
they see their relationship with India.
Apurwaraji says, "Is India prepared to
take a definitive leadership role in the
global south or does it still see itself
as a bridge between the west and the
east?" So you can do both, right? You
can do both. A nation like India, we are
on good terms, friendly terms with
everybody except for a couple of
countries.
We are not on good terms with China
because of the Chinese attitude towards
us. We aren't on good terms with
Pakistan because Pakistan is a US vasal
and and a terrorist nation and it exists
to bleed us.
Apart from these two countries, we have
Turkey that is pro Pakistan and very
strongly anti-India. Apart from a few
countries like these, a handful of
countries, we have good relations with
everybody. So even if we take up an
increasingly larger leadership role in
the global south as we are doing now, it
doesn't prevent us from being a bridge
between the west and the east for
example. We are we are on great terms
with all the Asian nations except one
essent except two
China and and Pakistan two and a half
Turkey also. Beyond that all other
nations in Asia are are with we have
great relations with them. We have great
relations with Russia. We have great
relations with well the west US kind of
it depends on the US but from our
perspective we would like to be great
friends with the US also. So if there is
a need for mediation between between the
US and Russia and the the two are not on
talking terms we could step in and and
perhaps uh mediate in some way or so or
something like that. So we are certainly
taking on a larger leadership role in
the global south. You saw that in during
the 2023 G20 summit during which we took
the initiative of bringing in the
African Union into the G20 which it
wasn't there before. We brought it in.
Um and uh right now the our prime
minister is on this trip to a large
number of global south nations. Uh so we
are doing that. We are actively doing
that taking on a larger and larger
leadership role. At the same time we can
be a bridge between the east and the
west. So both scenarios are true at the
same time. It's not either or. It's this
and that. Why not?
Wouldn't arm or PK says why don't Romani
people get the sympathy they deserve?
And can we Indians, civilians or
government do something to help them?
See the reason why Romanes are hated in
Europe? First of all, who are the Romani
people? They are also called gypsies.
They are nomadic people who live on the
outskirts of towns and cities and they
are horribly oppressed. Um they have
been they they first entered Europe
about a thousand years ago and they have
never been allowed to settle anywhere.
They always pushed from one place to
another. They have been horribly
oppressed in the past. They have been
enslaved. They have been killed in large
numbers. Killed for being Romani or
enslaved for for generations and so on.
And u even today they they are second
class citizens often even today they
don't have papers which is citizenship
documents of any country they they are
horribly oppressed and they are some of
the most talented people in Europe some
of the best footballers some of the best
musicians in Europe will have Romani
origins Robert Plant of Led Zeppelin one
of the greatest rock singers of all time
Romani uh Eric Ktona one of the greatest
Manchester United strikers Romani So
many apiro Andre Apirllo one of the
great Italians Romani I can give you so
many examples of of great Romani people
but they are horribly oppressed
flamingco music and dance of in Spain
Spain is known for flamco music and
flamco dance right that's Romani it's
not Spanish it's Romani but why do they
not give get the sympathy they deserve
because they are brown
because they used to be polytheists
Hindus who are the Romanis they are
descendants of Indians. How did they end
up in Europe?
How did they end up in Europe?
Well, Indians were enslaved by the
millions during the Gori Gori and
Gaznavi era eras. The Goris and the
Ghnavis and other Turks. They launched
raid after raid into India. Took took
away a lot of plunder, tremendous amount
of gold and jewels and wealth. destroyed
our temples like Subnath and took killed
all the men and took a lot of women and
children as slaves and took them into
central India to be sold in the bazars
of Bkhar and Sabarand Pashkand
Indians and eventually they ended up
with a surplus of enslaved Indian women
and children. So what they did they did
not want to commit a slaughter perhaps
on their soil. They were okay doing it
in India but to kill hundreds of
thousands of people perhaps in in
Central Asia they didn't want to do it
do do that. So they told him to get
lost, leave but you can't go back to
India, go westwards and that's how these
people ended up wandering all across
Europe. So there are the descendants of
our people the language the Romani
language it is closest
to Gujarati Rajasthani Punjabi these
languages western northern western
Indian languages
if you speak one of these Indian
languages you will actually understand
the Romani language to some extent.
Yeah. And they used to be Hindus but now
they they practice whatever religion
they have had to adopt in order to
survive. So they are still many of them
are still visibly Indian brown like us
and that's why they are hated and
oppressed in Europe. Even today even
today European nations treat them like
third class citizens. Even today in some
nations it's better. Turkey treats the
Romani people better than the other
European nations.
In in Turkey, the Romanis don't claim to
be Romani. They say we are Turks, we are
Muslims and we are proud Turks. As long
as you do that in Turkey, you'll be
fine. In Spain, some Romanis are very
rich because of flamingco music. In in
other countries, some footballers and
musicians are very rich and all, but
overall they are horribly oppressed.
Charlie Chaplan was a Romani
and so on. So, what can we Indians do to
help them? First of all, let's help
ourselves.
Okay. um we can support them on social
media etc. You can reach out to Romani
people and express your support towards
them and whatever. But if you if you
really want to help them, we have to
become a much more powerful, much
richer, much more powerful, much more
capable nation. Then we can help our
people.
Um, Nille says, "Is Britain America's
51st state?" Well, Canada is 51st.
Britain, maybe Britain is the 51st
state. Maybe Canada is 52nd. The five
eyes nations.
At the center, we have the US. Then you
have four other nations, the UK, Canada,
Australia and New Zealand. These are
essentially extensions of the US,
additional states of the US so to say.
And yeah, Britain is is their number one
vasal. So yeah, you could say it's the
51st state if you want to say why not.
Uh
now this is not a geopolitical question.
So why do you ask this sir? Many
civilizations and religions ended when
and so on. What do you think this
civilization will last for? How many
years? Which one? Which one? Sir, India.
India will last another 10,000 years.
Lindy effect.
Uh MK says, why didn't the US give its
nukes to Taiwan to keep China off
balance like it gave nukes to Pakistan
to keep India off balance?
Uh for the longest time, the US saw
China as as not as a rival but as one of
their tools, possibly an American tool.
So the Americans aided and abetted the
rise of China. They midwifed the rise of
China from the 1970s onwards. Ever since
the the the the Nixon Maine
and slowly China started becoming a
manufacturing nation and manufacturing
stuff that the west wanted, the US
wanted at very cheap rates and the
Americans thought that if China becomes
more prosperous, it will become
democratic.
That was kind of crushed.
Those aspirations were crushed in 1989
the Tanan Men Square massacre.
Uh but the Americans still thought that
they can keep China on their side. That
was delusional thinking. It's only
around 2008 2012 that that that period
of time that they started understanding
the China's actually arrival.
uh but by the time China had become
quite powerful and putting you know
giving nukes to Taiwan would have been a
very very very big provocation which
could have possibly risked immediate
action by China and maybe that's why
they did not do it. So there must be
some calculations behind this otherwise
they would have loved I'm sure if they
had seen this earlier they would have
probably put you know nukes in Taiwan.
Puruam says do nuclear submarines run on
nuclear fusion? No, they run on nuclear
fish. They have miniaturized nuclear
reactors which are fish reactors, not
fusion reactors.
Uh geopolitical dub says, do you see any
power struggle in the Chinese Communist
Party and the people's liberation army?
Well, there are indications something
could be happening. For example, uh
recently I saw some news that Xiinping
had purged the Chinese military
leadership of about a 100 generals. a
big churn in the leadership. Purging
generals means you sack them and perhaps
put them under trial or jail them. Um so
maybe this was u an initiative
whose intention was to ensure that there
is no disloyalty
in the Chinese Communist Part in in the
people's liberation army. um because the
people's liberation army is obviously
the the real that's where the real power
of the Chinese Communist Party comes
from. So that's why the PLA has to be
100% loyal to Xiinping. So in case there
are some people some commanders some
generals who have have shown subtle
hints or signs of dis disloyalty towards
Jinping that will be watched over time
and once a pattern is established they
will be marked for the next in line to
be purged and at a certain time you
suddenly purge a hund of them which
sends a message to everybody that you've
got to be 100% loyal. So that seems to
have happened recently. I saw the report
I think last week or something that
about a hundred highranking generals
were purged in the people's liberation
army. So there is something that keeps
on happening like this. You know that's
something that was very characteristic
of the Stalinist era in the USSR. That
was a terrifying era. I mean
such incredibly
capable generals were purged in in
Stalin in the during the Stalinist era.
Being purged means you were shot. your
whole family was shot. That's how it
was.
Uh so something like this seems to be
happening in China also periodically. In
the CCP also you will have that from
time to time. So you you do see this.
It's it's an ongoing process in the CCP
in the PLA. You you you have to be
paranoid if you're a dictator. You have
to be paranoid otherwise you never know
when you fall out of power. I mean uh
Lavender what happened to him? One day
he is the number one guy, next day he's
being shot in the USSR by Nikita Kruef.
That sort of thing. You have got to be
careful if you're a dictator in an
authoritarian nation like that. Um
Shashwat says, "Your thoughts on oil
exploration in the Andermans and the
extent and duration to to which it could
change our fortunes."
Well, we'll have to wait and watch.
We'll have to wait and watch. uh the
minister what's his name? Uh Mr. Hardib
Singh Puri he reasonably recently made a
statement that India may be on the verge
of a very major uh oil discovery in the
Anammans.
So we'll have to see about that. Uh
recently Guyana I think it was Guyana
that made a huge oil discovery and which
changed their fortunes. So if we stumble
upon something like that then it could
change our fortune. So I don't know. I
think we it's it's too early to count
it's it's too early to count what the
chickens don't count your chickens
before they hatch they say right so I
think it's too early to start start
celebrating or any such thing uh it
looks like there are indications in the
and where there's a lot of drilling
going on so so what happens when you're
prospecting for oil under under the
ocean is you drill and it's a very
expensive process each drilling platform
costs about $100 million
and you've got to drill a h 100 times
perhaps to find a big reserve of oil. So
you end up spending maybe maybe 10
billion
but then what you discover will way more
than make up for those $10 billion. So
you got to drill hundreds of such uh
test holes and shafts under the ocean
and maybe there are indications it looks
like that it's an oil richch region the
andan region. So let's keep our fingers
crossed and let's pray to the gods and
if we do discover something massive then
it will totally change
it will totally change India's fortunes.
If we discover something similar to what
Guyana has discovered we become a major
oil exporter in a few years. We not only
are able to uh ensure that we have our
own supplies of oils. We don't have to
import anything else but we could end up
becoming a net exporter just like
Kuwait, Iraq, Saudi Arabia or whatever
Iran. Yeah, I mean imagine how that
changes the equations, geopolitical
equations in the world. So that could
happen. That's the scenario. But nothing
has been discovered yet. No announcement
has been made yet. So let's wait and
watch. But if it happens, fantastic.
Uh Purotradan says we should develop
fusion bombs. In 1998
when we tested five nuclear weapons, one
of those weapons was a two-stage device,
three-stage device actually. The first
stage is a chemical explosion. Chemical
explosions, explosions like TNT or
whatever. Okay, doesn't matter what it
is. Chemical explosion. That's the first
stage. The second stage was fish. So the
chemical explosion rams the second the
two halves of the fish device together
and that gives rise to a fish explosion.
Fish chain reaction. That's a standard
fishision bomb. But there's a third
stage. The fish implosion
will implode a third a core which will
then undergo fusion.
And that fusion reaction gives off way
more energy as an output than the fish
reaction ever can. So that's a two-stage
or three-stage thermonuclear fish fusion
device also called a hydrogen bomb. We
tested that in 1998.
So we have we have that in our arsenal.
A fish and fusion device a thermonuclear
device. A hydrogen bomb like that's what
they used to call that that device in
the 20th century when I was a little
kid. Hydrogen bomb.
So we have that we have f fusion
devices.
Uh
Benjamin Nathanos says can I become
India's most reliable long-term
strategic partner in the Middle East
surpassing Iran or even Saudi Arabia?
Lessons should India learn from me?
Israel is to a large extent a very
reliable uh partner for India in in
military technology in military
cooperation. There's a lot of
convergence of interests that we have
with Israel. Um for example um we have
developed certain weapons systems
together. The the Barack missile very
very good missile. Okay. It's the
probably the only missile that can take
out a Brahmos.
So we have that our ships
our our warships. Okay. They will have
Brahmos missiles as well as Barak
missiles. So we have the poison and the
antidote on the same ship together. So
the barak missile it can be used for a
variety of things and uh that's an
Indo-Israeli project. Then we have the
harup loitering munition loitering drone
kamikaz dr dr dr dr dr dr dr dr dr dr dr
dr dr dr dr dr dr dr dr dr drone it's
not a loitering drone it's a kamikaz
drone right suicide drone uh that is
being built manufactured in India and
that's an Israeli design. So we have a
lot going on together and we have other
kinds of cooperation as well um
technological cooperation, strategic
cooperation possibly and much more. So
we have excellent relations uh with
Israel. We also have excellent relations
with other partners in the in in West
Asia, Saudi Arabia, the UAE, Iran is a
good reasonably good partner for us. No
question about that. Uh and and other
nations like uh Oman for example uh and
uh and so on.
So yeah, that's that is the situation
and I'm sure that India and Israel
relationship can become even better in
the future. They would not ever be
opposed to that. Yeah, they will they
would welcome that.
Grock says Russia and China are which
type of communists? Well, Russia is no
longer a communist nation. Russia is not
a communist nation. The USSR was a
communist nation.
What type? A Marxist Leninist, I would
say. Uh China is is still a de facto
communist nation. Uh Maoist communism no
longer Marxist Leninist but the Mao
style of communism used to be on in
vogue. Now it is Xi Jinping thought that
drives the ideological uh
part of of how China is is governed. So
that's the flavor of communism that you
have in China today. But China is also a
capitalist nation. It's an out andout
capitalist nation with some socialistic
characteristics and they like to harp
upon the socialist part, but it's not
really a very socialistic country
overall. It's an authoritarian regime.
It's a dictatorship for sure, but it's
still a very uh capitalistic with a lot
of state controllers. It's it's a
hybrid. It's a mishmash of things, but
it works well for them. Okay.
Sergeant Skylin says, "What will happen
to the carry engine program?" I think
it's going to be used for UAVs.
UAVs is uh unmanned aerial vehicles.
Maybe UCAVs, unmanned combat aerial
vehicles, maybe something else. And
maybe it'll be continued in that manner.
So I think it'll continue, but it will
it's no longer going to be considered
for uh fighter jets, fighter planes.
Maybe something else is a foot. We'll
have to see about that. We'll we'll see.
Benjamin Netanyahu says, "Why do I keep
posting wrong maps of India? Explain."
Well, I'll have to ask you sir about
that. Why do you do that? Yeah, I can't
read your mind, sir. Can I? Uh, look,
Israel and India, we have a lot of
strategic convergence, a lot of
convergence of interest, but we have
differences as well. And yeah, that's
how that's why this happens. For
example, on on a lot of lot on on many
occasions, we vote against Israel when
it comes to UN resolutions in on on some
occasions at least. And we have some
differences here and there, which is why
these things happen.
Avir says Turkey is now supplying
Bangladesh. Can we not preempt this like
Israel before it escalates and becomes a
three-front situation for us?
You can't just unilaterally start
bombing countries and all that. Okay?
Israel can do it and get away with it.
we can't uh and and Bangladesh will
never become a three-front situation for
us. We obviously have to keep an eye on
what's happening in Bangladesh. But
Bangladesh is simply incapable of
challenging India militarily no matter
what they think or what they say. So we
have to keep an eye on what's happening
and in case there is something in the
future we can neutralize the threat.
Okay, that that won't be difficult for
us.
Uh
Achintia Ananda says, "What's the op
optimal plan for the Indian Navy
currently? Area denial or power
projection in the Indian Ocean, which
means carriers versus nuclear
submarines." Uh the optimal plan,
see, let me put it this way. Um let's
say you are learning how to play cricket
and you want to be a batsman. So what's
the first thing you learn as a batsman?
You learn how to block the ball, how to
play defense, right? Play defense. You
first have to ensure you don't get out.
The ball doesn't go through the gap and
hits your stumps, right? You want to
ensure that that that that's taken care
of first. So the first thing you do is
to tighten your defenses and make it
impossible for somebody to to get you
out. So in my opinion, what should be
done about the Indian Navy? First of
all, we have to be superb at defense.
Which means we need to have a very
powerful coast guard all across our
eastern western coast. Maybe hundreds of
ships or boats, patrol vessels.
Then we need to have once that is done,
we need to have
distributed lethality which is warships
and submarines in judicious numbers. And
uh look what what is the measure? How do
you measure the lethality of a of a
naval force of a navy? Is it number of
ships? If I have 300 ships, I've got a
powerful navy. No, you don't measure the
lethality of a navy by the number of
ships. The lethality of a navy is
measured by the number of missiles you
can deploy on any given day. On average,
on any given day, how many missiles can
you deploy at sea? That's the lethality
of your navy. Okay?
So you need to distribute the lethality
which means that don't concentrate
everything all the firepower in a few
ships. Distribute it across lots of
ships far and wide across the ocean. So
you need to have a mix of different
kinds of warships. You need to have
corvettes. You need to have destroyers.
You need to have cruisers. Cruisers is
still operational whatever. U missile
boats and submarines and different kinds
of submarines. Attack submarines. uh
missile uh nuclear submarines and
whatnot and that once again I would not
want to do power projection right now.
You want to essentially u have a very
visible presence in the eastern and
western Indian oceans. Indian oceans
which is the so-called Arabian Sea and
the so-called Bay of Bengal should be
visible and ever present the Indian
presence in the region. And then once
you have developed all of this that you
can on demand deploy your your ships to
a certain region maybe the Gulf of uh
the the the the the straight of Mala or
the straight of Hormuz or the Gulf of
the straight of Bab al-Mandde or
whatever once you have that ability
that's where you can think of uh you
know having more ships or maybe more
aircraft carriers or something. So I
think that's how you should do it. You
should do it step by step. Start with
the very basics with with just defense.
Once you your defense is impregnable,
then you start developing more options,
more offensive options. Then you can
start developing power production
abilities to various states straits and
all that. Then you can have can have
aircraft carriers. You also have the
Andermans where you can deploy fighter
planes and submarines. So that's like an
unsinkable aircraft carrier. That's how
it should be done. Maybe you should have
a 20 30 year plan and ideally you the
Indian Navy should have in excess of 300
warships of different kinds including
submarines. It's very feasible. It will
take time but why not do it?
Okay.
Uh Karan says, "Could the North Caucasus
become a geopolitical fault line given
its native peoples like the Vä and the
Sassins are non-indouropean and
non-Indoarian and hold distinct and
Islamic and ethnic identities unlike
their neighbors." Uh look, it's it's
kind of like the Balkans. The Caucasus
region is is complicated. Let me put the
map on. Okay. Lots of different
ethnicities, small ethnic groups. It's
situ situation very similar to the
Balkcon region. So the Caucasus region
is the region between the Black Sea and
the and the Caspian Sea. Okay. And you
have these nations here Azarbaijan, you
have Armenia, you have Arus, you have
Georgia, you have Russia and Russia also
in the caucuses. have the Chachchan
people, the the the the uh Dagistani
people and also you have all these
different smaller ethnic groups like the
Sarcassians, the Wak u the Laz people
and so much more the Laz people. Yeah,
you may have the Laz people also perhaps
over here. Uh so and and there are lots
of old feuds and enmities and all that
over here. I'm not sure if the
sarcasians are non-indo-uropean.
The chachchans for sure are
Indo-Iranian.
Uh for sure the chachans, the
Dagistanis, I'm not sure. So it's it's I
myself I'm not very clear about exactly
which ethnicity
belongs to which larger group. As far as
I see, the Sarassians are Indo-Uropeans.
Uh any anyway, that's that's not the
point. The point is that uh it's it's a
mishmash of ethnicities. It's got a very
convoluted history. Lots of old feuds
and enmities are there. Uh but as long
as there's a big power in the region or
big powers, all those little feuds and
all don't matter.
So if there is if if see right now the
major power in the region is obviously
Russia, you also have Turkey, you also
have Iran. So it's at the confluence of
of Russia, Turkey and Iran this region.
Okay. Uh and historically it was part of
greater Iran,
right? Um
but the major power today is Russia. And
as long as Russia's power is there and
it power ability is there, all these
little little rivalries and all they
will not really matter. But you are
right, it's a very complex region just
like the Balkans. It's slightly less
complex than the Balkans, but yeah, you
can compare it to the Balkan region. uh
it can become a geopolitical fault line
and obviously you have instability
there. You have the Azarbaijan Armenia
conflict. You've had issues in Georgia
in the past. There's the Turkish
influence. There's Iranian influence.
There's the Iran Azarbaijan issue. The
Azarbaijan Armenia issue. The Russia
Georgia issue and and so much more. The
Americans also are trying to do stuff
there. Turkey is trying to create a
panther corridor. So it is a
geopolitical fault line. But as long as
Russia is powerful enough, things will
be under control.
Game Boy says how are we sovereign if we
rely on US tech operating systems apps
cloud we don't have jet engine
technology
we have no jet engine technology low G20
tax 11% of GDP G20 tax I'm not sure what
anti-India social media freebies nation
building check operation sundu for
reality what's your question we are not
sovereign we are sovereign we have
issues we have less issues than many
other nations trust me and what about
operation sindu for reality. We we won
operation sindu sindur. Are you one of
those people who believes that we lost
operation sindur? Are you one of those
people who believe that? Well, if that's
the case, you need a reality check. But
see, you are right that we rely on US
tech. Our operating systems are are all
American systems. All the platforms we
use, social media platforms and so on
are American platforms. We don't have
our jet engine technology. Uh social
media is very antidia. You're right
about that. freebies over nation
building. True. I can list 20 more
issues that we have. But we are still
sovereign. Why are we still sovereign?
We have no foreign military bases on our
soil.
That's one, right? We have our own
currency. That's number two. We control
our borders. We have issues at the
borders. No question. Manipur is a big
disaster zone right now. H nobody wants
to talk about it. We have P which is
under Pakistani occupation. Akai Chin
which is under Chinese occupation. China
claims Arunachal. Now we claim Tibbe
perhaps say that Tibet is is disputed.
We have issues but whatever we control
we control. We have sovereignty
over our territory.
We have sovereignty over our economy
because we have our own currency and we
can set our policies. We have
sovereignty over our military. We don't
have any foreign military bases on our
soil and we don't have our military
under foreign command like we have in
the NATO nations and so much more. So
because of all those macro factors, we
are still a sovereign nation which most
other other nations can't claim. We have
issues. No question. Every nation has
issues. But let's not be defeist and
start crying. H let's not do that. We'll
solve the issues.
Nille says Trump is now president but
still CIA is unable to find motive
behind the Trump assassination attempt.
Why so? The public will the public never
know the motive? The public will never
know the motive. Does the public even
today know why JFK was assassinated or
who who did that?
H and is Trump chastising the CIA
for not uh discovering the motive?
Most likely Trump knows what happened.
But the public doesn't need to know
about it. That's how it goes. The public
is not important.
The public doesn't matter.
The public doesn't know to know doesn't
need to know a lot of things. Even
today, you don't know who who killed JFK
and why he was killed. There's a lot you
don't know about. And you're not
supposed to know about this. We are we
are not supposed to know about this. We
don't matter, right? We are public.
Public doesn't matter. Democracy, what
democracy? Haha.
Godliness says Turkey and China openly
help Pakistan in the May conflict. Yeah.
Do you believe us or any other nation
help India the same way? No. No. If not,
then does comprehensive strategic global
partnerships are just word play? We
don't have any comprehensive global
partnership with anybody.
We have no alliance, military alliance
with anybody whatsoever. So what word
play? There's no word play here. We
stand alone. When Iran was hammered by
the Americans, who came and stood with
Iran? They had this war with Israel,
right? They hammered Israel. They
smashed lots of neighborhoods in Tel
Aviv with their missiles and Tel Aviv
was was devastated. Then Tehran was
devastated. Iranian cities were
devastated by the Israelis. Um
Iranian IRGC military personnel were
killed. Their nuclear scientists were
killed. Then the Americans hammered for
Natans is Fahan with their bunker
busting bombs and so on. All of this
happened. Who came and stood with Iran?
Tell me. Did Russia come and stand with
Iran? Iran is selling is is supplying
Russia with shahed drones right for the
Ukraine war. Did Russia come and stand
with Iran?
Iran is selling very cheap oil to China.
Did China come and stand with Iran?
Mm-m.
That is the nature of the world, my
friends. You think only India is alone?
No. Everybody is alone.
Everybody is alone. Nobody's going to
come and stand with you when when things
go wrong.
So the why why do we need somebody to
stand with us? We are 1.4 billion of us,
right? Isn't that enough?
So my point is we don't have any
strategic global partnership or or or
any military alliance with anybody a
partnerships and all is like you say
like you're right it's all word play. Oh
we are great partners and we we we
shared we share so many values blah blah
blah. It's all words. Nobody's going to
come and stand with us. The Americans
have supplied Pakistan with nuclear
weapons. You think they'll come and
stand with us?
They operate the Nurhan air base. The
Pakistani nuclear weapons are under the
control of an American general. You
think the Americans will still come and
stand with us? What they want? Obviously
they won't.
H AL says deputy chief of army staff
says we are fighting three enemies
Pakistan, Turkey, China access but
initially he said fourth and corrected
instead of three enemies. If he meant
four then who?
Well see you see you have to understand
Pakistan is not one entity it is two
entities. There are east Pakistan and
west Pakistan. I hope that answers your
question right does it?
If if that's what he what he meant. So I
would say that if he said that then
probably that's what he meant perhaps.
Perhaps. Okay. Grock says US will not
want Russia to grow economically and
would always want it to be in conflict.
Question mark. China too wants that and
Russia has golden chance to get
ceasefire on his term. Why war still?
What ceasefire? What golden chance?
Where? Where?
Do you think you can believe you can
trust America's word? If America gives
you an assurance, do you think you can
trust it? The Americans promised the the
the Russians that you allow the
reunification of East and West Germany
in 1991 and we will not expand NATO one
inch eastwards. They promised that. What
happened?
What happened? You think you can trust
their word? Even if they sign an
agreement, you think you can trust them?
Even if it's in writing with their stamp
and seal and signature of Donald Trump,
you think you can trust them? What
happened with the JCPOA, the Iran
nuclear deal? It was signed, right, by
the US president. Trump walked away from
it.
All these promises and treaties mean
nothing. You have to look at your
national interest. You to look at your
threat perception, your threat uh the
threat environment, and you have to make
your decisions based on that. The
Americans, if they say that, okay, we
will give you a ceasefire in the Ukraine
war, we'll end the Ukraine war. It means
that they want it to to to temporarily
be paused as long as they can take care
of something else and then they will
restart it anytime they like it
when you are in a maybe more
disadvantageous position. There's no
golden chance. Golden chance. What
golden chance? Please, please, sir, wake
up. There's no golden chance.
Rational reporter says Armenia is so
interesting. Small nation, low
population, Abrahamic, surrounded by
enemies, fighting for survival. Reminds
me of another nation. Can we groom it as
our own mini attack talk in Central Asia
like US did in Middle East? No. No.
That's a nation that's under threat of
being destroyed.
And who do we attack with it? We don't
want to.
What do we gain by let's say
hypothetically we use Armenia as an
attack dog. How does it serve India's
national interest? to understand to to
answer the question that I just asked.
How does it serve India's national
interest? Ask yourself, what is India's
national interest? What is it? Is it to
start fights everywhere in the world?
That's not our national interest. Our
national interest is to grow our economy
to 10, 15, 20 trillion dollars and move
forward. Keep moving forward. That's our
national interest.
Our national interest is not to poke our
noses in other people's affairs. then
it'll encourage others to poke their
noses into our affairs more.
Why should we groom Armenia as our
attack dog? It'll destroy Armenia first
of all. It's a good nation, good people.
And secondly, how does it serve our
national interest? What what do we get
out of it? I don't understand.
It doesn't serve our national interest
at all. It's not a good good idea by any
means. So my point is this. See, I
criticized what you said, right? But
this is what you should take away from
from my answer.
You should know what the national
interest is always when you're thinking
of what should India do. Should we do
this? Should we do that? Should we take
this this this course of action? That
course of action. Whatever course of
action you're thinking about, ask
yourself, how does it serve my national
interest?
And to answer the question, you have to
know what the national interest is.
The national interest is the long-term
security prosperity
of the nation and its people. And the
nation and the people should thrive in
the long term. That's the national
interest. And what is imperative for
that? Economic growth. What is
imperative for that? Long-term peace.
Right? And sometimes to make peace, you
have to fight wars. So you can have
long-term peace only if you take get rid
of Pakistan as an entity next to us. So
that's why operation zindur makes sense.
But fighting having Armenia turn into
attack dog. How does it serve our
national interest? Okay, that's how you
think. That's called critical thinking.
Okay. S P says uh loving your
understanding America series. Thank you
sir. When will you drop the next
episode? Excited for it. Well uh yeah uh
it's already recorded. It needs to be
edited. It takes some time. Right now
I'm doing a whole lot of stuff. I need
to cut down on some on some on some
things. So, yeah, it'll it'll come out
soon in the next maybe
maybe two three weeks, the next episode,
and then it'll hopefully become more
regular. There's been a little bit of
hiatus, but it will soon be taken care
of. All right.
Uh,
science nerd said, "How come you
suddenly added Israel in the sovereign
nations list? Earlier, you did not
include Israel." You see you have to
reassess constantly
and if you have made mistakes in the
past you have to correct them. You
cannot be stuck with your ego and said I
said only four so only four. No I missed
out on Israel
and I I have corrected myself. I had
made a mistake. Israel should have been
included because when you think of
things properly and look at each nation
thoroughly then you will realize that
Israel is indeed a sovereign nation
despite whatever. So I corrected myself
and I have now added Israel to the
sovereign nation list. You have to be
willing to change your opinion otherwise
you never progress in life. You will
never learn. All right.
Okay. Okay. Jay Thiari says Indian
global India global power. How shackled
by colonial laws, bureaucracy,
corruption, poor business ease, broken
education system, weak R&D, trash, civic
sense, decay, sick institutions, health
neglect, rising divisions, 19th century
judiciary. Sir,
I am not saying India will be a global
power anytime soon. India should just be
a strong power in the in the region. Uh
India should be able to ward off China
and all these
You are absolutely 100% right. All these
issues you've listed, they are indeed
things that are keeping India down. So
many problems.
What you are essentially showing us is
that India has never decolonized and we
are continuing with the colonial system
and the colonial baggage and the
colonial garbage and the and and the and
the and the rotten colonial system and
all those all those compromised
institutions and so much more and that's
creating more more divisions and more
fissures and fragmentation and etc all
of that in India no question about it
and despite that we are rising as an
economy for somehow. So imagine if we
solve all these problems, what will
happen? India will be unstoppable. But
the pro the question is who's going to
solve this and how long will it take? I
think it'll take a long time to solve
these problems in one go. You will need
a superhuman leader. We've had such
leaders in the past once in a few
hundred years. It's been a few hundred
years since we had something somebody
like that. The last great leader I can
think of is probably Chhatraata Shivaji
Maharaj and some of the Peshawas. Um
before that you had the the father-son
duo of Rajend of Rajar Raj and Rajendra
Chola. So you need somebody of that
stature of that
willpower and fortitude to rise in
India. If a person like that rises then
everything will be solved. It'll be
difficult but it will happen. So maybe
it'll take 50 years for this to be
solved. By the time if we can just make
decent progress, 6% 7% economic growth
per year, even that will make us a
powerful nation. So we have problems, no
question, lots of problems, but let's
not be all defeatist. Let's be
optimistic. No matter how bad things
are, things could be worse and things
can get better. So let's be optimistic.
We have problems, but we have to look
for solutions and not just sit down and
lie down and go to sleep. That's not the
solution.
Gro says today's geopolitical situation
if Espatel had been first PM I don't
know you can
a thousand things could have happened I
don't know that's all hypothetical
what's the point of thinking about that
let's let's be realistic and look at
where where we are today right and where
we could go
puro Pradan says why don't we become a
vasal of the US and we'll be safe look
at Japan Japan is very safe TFR is dead
the economy is dead and Japan will cease
to exist as nation in the next 50 years
there will be no Japanese left. Very
safe. Look at South Korea. Same
situation. Very safe. Look at Germany.
Where are the German people today? They
are being overrun by immigrants. Does
Germany even exist as a nation? Very
safe. What are you talking about? You're
looking at things from a very narrow
self-centered perspective. Oh yeah, I
will have better quality of life. I will
have US US cereal to eat in the morning.
I will get import from the US. my my
phone will be 10% cheaper. That's how
you're looking at things. But you're not
looking not looking at the long-term
effect on the nation. It'll destroy the
nation. It'll destroy our civilization.
If you become a US vasal in 15 20 years,
80% of Indians will be Christians.
Nothing against any specific religion,
but this industrial scale demographic
re-engineering will happen, which is
already happening to a large extent in
the country. It'll just accelerate. Do
we want that?
What will be safe? Are you kidding me?
We'll be destroyed.
Raul says, "What geopolitical shifts
would happen if if Iran became
Zoroastrian again? And how could that
happen when half of the population
descends from Caucasian immigrants who
followed indigenous cockas, not
Indo-Iranian religions?"
Well, that's a lot of hypotheticals
here. I mean, Iran is not under any
danger of becoming Zoroastrin. in I I
hear that a lot of people in Iran no
longer follow Islam. That's what I hear.
It may be true, it may be false. I don't
know. Uh but are they reverting to
Zorastianism? I don't think they are.
Maybe they they don't know how to
perhaps whatever it is. See, but if Iran
becomes Zorastian again,
uh first of all, you're right. Half the
population is non-Persian, right? U of
course you had Zoroastrianism which was
spread beyond present day Iran. the
Caucasus region. I think it was the
roast before Armenia became Christian.
Um
so
let's say hypothetically
the whole of Persia becomes Zoroastrian
then it will be very different obviously
uh
how what geopolitical shift would happen
I think Iran would become more neutral
or look the or maybe not maybe not when
Iran was the roast it was at the
pinnacle of its power imperial power the
hakshamish dynasty aid dynasty Right.
The househatra
these great kings,
great emperors who fought the Europeans
if if if Persia becomes Zostran again,
they'll again go expand westwards which
will not be very good for our friends in
Israel. Right? Of course, it was the
Zarastrians who who saved the Jews from
u who gave the Jews shelter in Persia
during the occupation by the Assyrians
and so on. That's a whole history. But
yeah, Zoroast and Persia was an imperial
power. It'll become friendly with India
and it will it will again start its its
imperial campaigns against the West. So
that could happen. Who knows? Who knows?
Wamshi Kalem says$125 trill trillion
dollar economy is in our own national
interest. I completely agree. Next stop
is 125 trillion. Totally agree. Next 50
years right
uh puram says I know that I just wanted
to know from you what did you know if
why don't you become a vasal of the US
that thing. Yeah. So then I I I I then
gave you the answer that you wanted. So
all right there we go.
Okay. Let us maybe take a few more
questions and then we will end today's
live stream. Um
let us see
I don't know do we have more questions
there's a lot of discussion happening in
the chat.
Uh okay let's take this question as the
last question. Please stop asking
questions. This this will be the last
one for today. Okay. The question is in
go
government exam. Okay. In government
exam if question is about the highest
peak of India. Uh K2 and Kjanga are both
in the option but K2 is wrong. It's in a
disputed area. The government
organizations are a part of government.
Government doesn't accept them as Indian
areas but want people to be vocal. What
is why this hypocrisy?
Okay. Okay. So in the government exam
the question is what's the highest peak
of India they they've given options and
in the options you have K2 and Kenjunga
and if you take if you if you select K2
which is in P
they'll say it's wrong. Is is that what
you're saying?
Well that should be it should be right
because see Everest is in Nepal half
Nepal half Tibet. Uh Tibet is a disputed
territory of course. uh but K2 is in PK
which is Indian territory. So the right
answer should be K2 and if in a
government exam they saying K2 is wrong
then those people need to have their
heads examined and their loyalties
examined loyalty to the nation right um
so yeah this this happens at lower
levels this happens at lower
bureaucratic levels these bureaucrats
you know they they go through the IAS
exam and whatnot and I don't know what
they what what garbage you have to study
for the I is exam it essentially makes
you an antinational it makes you hate
Indian civilization
So what can I say? It's it's terrible
that that such things happen. U there
are obviously many high many superb is
officers. No question. But those are few
and far between. Most unfortunately
I don't know what to say about them. So
yeah, this is this is wrong. K2 is the
right answer. K2 is the right answer.
Okay, there's one more question. This is
the last for today. U so drones at the
border over my home. Operation Hindu
we've won but 18 India 181 19 in G20 tax
GDP ratio R&D low talent we must build
in inside like government using Indian
OS for example but no one talks no we
should have an Indian OS no question
uh let it be based on Linux or whatever
but it should be an Indian OS developed
in India and be completely Indian I
completely agree with you uh the amount
of money we are investing in R&D the
government is investing in R&D is is
terribly low it's shameful obviously
talent will leave if If you treat talent
horribly, talent will leave.
So you are right about these things.
You're right. No question about it. We
have so many problems in this country.
They need to be addressed. And that's
why I sometimes you will see me very
frustrated especially when I talk about
the education system which is the root
cause of all all of these issues are
indalent. I mean the way we treat our
talent in the education system, it tells
talent please leave the country, you are
not welcome here. And then with the way
we treat talent in other sectors, it
tells talent if you want to do well,
leave the country. You are not welcome
here. In India, we welcome mediocrity.
That's the system and that's what needs
to be fixed. So you are right. No
question about it. You're absolutely
right. All right friends, whatever the
problems we face, we're going to do
well. We're going to surmount them and
we're going to win. We will remain
positive. We will not be pessimistic.
will remain optimistic and we will all
work as hard as possible to succeed. All
right, so thank you so much for all your
questions. I really appreciate them all.
It was a fun fun live stream today. I
really enjoyed the questions and I look
forward to seeing you all next week.
Please keep asking questions. Please
keep asking questions of me. Please keep
asking questions of yourselves. Keep
learning. Keep raising your standards.
And uh yeah, I'll see you next week. If
you if you would like to like put a like
down there, please do. And I'll see you
I look forward to seeing you all next
week. Thank you so much. Take care.
Bye-bye. See you soon.